Guide to the Golden Gate International Exposition Publicity Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Golden Gate International Exposition Publicity Records
1938-1940
WA MSS S-2889
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1
(1 box)
Golden Gate International Exposition ( 1939-1940 San Francisco, Calif.)
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Public Relations Documents, 1938-1940. II. Publicity Materials, 1940.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Golden Gate International Exposition
The Golden Gate International Exposition was held in California in 1940 on Treasure Island in the San Francisco Bay. The 1940 exposition, themed "Fun in the Forties," was the second iteration of the exposition, after 1939's "Pageant of the Pacific" exposition.
Scope and Contents
The publicity records contain output of the public relations arm of the 1940 Golden Gate International Exposition. The records document the activities of the exposition and the promotional effort required of the exposition's public relations department. The public relations documents comprise the bulk of the records and are newspaper, magazine, and radio press releases, typescript mimeographed. The public relations documents concern the 1940 exposition, but one file of background information on the 1939 exposition is also present. The publicity materials include one folder of a series of forty-five feature stories, typescript mimeographed, by the California editor and writer Jack Cook, presenting a daily tour of the exposition's exhibits.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Marc Selvaggio on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2008
Exhibitions -- California -- San Francisco; Fairs -- California -- San Francisco; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Description and travel; Promotional materials; Cook, Jack, active 1940; Golden Gate International Exposition ( 1939-1940 San Francisco, Calif.)
- Public Relations Documents, 1938-1940; Series I
  - Press releases issued before the opening of the Golden Gate International Exposition's 1939 season, 1938 October-1939 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    30 press releases and stories
  - Press releases, 1940 January 24-March 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Press releases, including radio scripts and a "word picture" for the exhibition.
  - Pre-opening day press releases, 1940 March 27-July 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    71 press releases.
  - Pre-opening day press releases, 1940 April 1-May 31 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    69 pre-opening day press releases.
  - Press releases and articles, 1940 April 1-May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    54 press releases and articles prepared by the publicity department's Magazine Division, including magazine articles, a calendar of events, and a list of approved concessions, including "Midget Auto Races," "Mental Act No. 2," and "Monkey Speedway."
  - Press releases, 1940 February-September (Box 1, Folder 6)
    35 releases by the California State Fair Commission on the state's participation in the Exposition and events, including "Redwood Empire at Treasure Island," "Expo Livestock Coliseum," and To Order - History Re-created."
  - Press releases, 1940 May 25-September 20[?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    85 press releases listing the "Program for Special Days," or the daily events of the exposition, with a piece on Opening Day.
  - Daily attendance records, 1940 May 27-September 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Attendance records, recorded by hour and by means of arrival (e.g. ferry, auto, bus, or others).
  - Press releases, 1940 June 1-11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    61 releases on events held during this period of the exhibition, including a "Festival of Negro Music."
  - Press releases, 1940 June 11-June 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    67 releases for activities during this period, including on the Gayway, Real Estate Day, Twin Day, and feeding people at the Midget Colony.
  - Press releases, 1940 July 1-31 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    136 releases for the month of July on the topics and activities on Treasure Island.
  - Press releases, 1940 July 15-July 31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    90 releases, articles, and scripts.
  - Press releases, 1940 August (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Press releases, 1940 August 4-September 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    50 releases on the "Daily Exposition Programs," including Gertrude Lawrence Day, National Association of the Deaf Day, Temple of Religion Day, and Coast Guard Day.
  - Press releases, 1940 September 1-29 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    76 releases.
- Publicity Material, 1940; Series II
  - Jack Cook Stories, [1940] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    45 feature stories by Jack Cook, California editor and writer, presenting a day-by-day tour of the individual exhibits on Treasure Island.